<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools and Techniques on Noverse</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/tags/tools-and-techniques/</link><description>Recent content in Tools and Techniques on Noverse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 13:33:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noverse.github.io/tags/tools-and-techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get it Brilliant</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/09/17/get-it-brilliant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 13:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/09/17/get-it-brilliant/</guid><description>When it comes to software, there should be no such thing as &amp;lsquo;good enough&amp;rsquo; software. Yet most software fits this bill, it does something &amp;lsquo;good enough&amp;rsquo; to get the work done or even sell. Even though the user has to jump through hoops to do so, or create workarounds to make the whole thing work.
At Noverse, we don&amp;rsquo;t make &amp;lsquo;good enough&amp;rsquo; software. Our products must be brilliant, they must be flexible, they must be proven correct, they must get the job done without workarounds, they must be fast and easy to use, they must be amazing.</description></item><item><title>Alpha Testing</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/07/31/alpha-testing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 15:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/07/31/alpha-testing/</guid><description>Everybody talks about Beta testing, unit testing and integration testing, but there is little on Alpha testing out there. At Noverse, we do them all.
What is Alpha Testing? If you follow the Wikipedia definition, Alpha testing happens when the product is incomplete and yet still handed over to a testing team inside the organization. And Beta testing happens when the customer gets to test pre-release versions.
For us, a small indie developer, we have no separate testing or Q&amp;amp;A team, so our Alpha testing is done with our customers as well.</description></item><item><title>To a nail, everything looks like a hammer</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/03/05/to-a-nail-everything-looks-like-a-hammer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 10:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/03/05/to-a-nail-everything-looks-like-a-hammer/</guid><description>One of the most common scenarios I see is companies using Excel to run their core business. Whenever a new report is needed, new analysis, new form, data conversion, no matter the task, they turn to Excel. They make everything look like a nail, and the only tool they understand is Excel, so they use it like a hammer. The result? Manual processes, inconsistent data, key-person dependencies, inflexibility, pain and suffering.</description></item><item><title>Delivering Solutions: Corporate, Appliance or Hosted</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/01/21/delivering-solutions-corporate-appliance-or-hosted/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 16:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/01/21/delivering-solutions-corporate-appliance-or-hosted/</guid><description>I have just spent the past few weeks working on the initial design of a new product for Noverse. The question was how to deliver the solution to our customers. We could:
Install it on their infrastructure - lets call that the &amp;ldquo;Corporate Model&amp;rdquo; Deliver a prebuilt computer with the software on it - lets call that the &amp;ldquo;Appliance Model&amp;rdquo; Host it on our gear accessible over the internet - lets call it the &amp;ldquo;Hosted Model&amp;rdquo; Lets look at each in turn.</description></item><item><title>How to use software</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/09/09/how-to-use-software/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 13:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/09/09/how-to-use-software/</guid><description>I was having a discussion the other day about my next OS X application and the responses I got were that there was a free web way or a free command line way to do what my app will do, so why bother?
It got me thinking about how I use software, how other people use software, how people tell me how to use software and how I tell other people how to use software.</description></item><item><title>How to deal with an iPhone crash report, a better way</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/08/10/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report-a-better-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 11:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/08/10/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report-a-better-way/</guid><description>There is an easier way to deal with an iPhone crash report than in my previous article How to deal with an iPhone crash report. And here it is.
Before you release the app Run a Build and Archive in Xcode, making sure that the version you are building is the one you are sending out (beta release or final release, properly code signed).
Xcode builds the app, the places the app, its dSYM file, a plist and the ipa file in ~/Library/Mobiledevice/Archived Applications/&amp;lt;UUID&amp;gt;/ where it can be found and managed by Organizer and by spotlight.</description></item><item><title>Beta testing is hard, but oh so worth it</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/07/31/beta-testing-is-hard-but-oh-so-worth-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 13:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/07/31/beta-testing-is-hard-but-oh-so-worth-it/</guid><description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve built the next killer app, and it looks and feels and works exactly how you dreamed, designed, planned and sweated to make it. Even the non-programming stuff is as brilliant as you can make it, the web site, the artwork, the documentation and the press goodies. As far as you are concerned, it&amp;rsquo;s ready to ship - and real developers ship after all.
Not so fast, bucakaroo! Best to beta test first.</description></item><item><title>Testing the new Web Design</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/07/16/testing-the-new-web-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 10:50:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/07/16/testing-the-new-web-design/</guid><description>I decided to revamp the noverse.com website before it became too complex. The original site had too many pages, and tons of html was being repeated. Every change had to be made in too many places, and as a developer, that violates the rules.
So, I switched from HTML/CSS to PHP-HTML/CSS. Easy. The only PHP I am using is to include common blocks of code, like the navigation bar, sidebar and footer.</description></item><item><title>Replacing the Address Book Picker</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/03/11/replacing-the-address-book-picker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 12:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/03/11/replacing-the-address-book-picker/</guid><description>In the first release of Emergency List, I used the default ABPeoplePickerNavigationController to allow users to add emergency contacts from their iPhone Address Book. Real users found it confusing, so I wrote my own.
What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with the Apple implementation? The requirement is for the user to pick a phone number for a contact.
The implementation requires you to launch an address book picker which displays a list of contact names - just the names and nothing else.</description></item><item><title>How to deal with an iPhone crash report</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/03/03/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 22:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/03/03/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report/</guid><description>Kudos to the app review team at Apple, they found a crasher in the update to Emergency List that I recently submitted. They even took the time to step through and document what they did exactly to reproduce the error.
From their email:
1. Launch app connected to a network 2. Tap Emergency List 3. Tap the Add button 4. Tap Add from Address Book 5. App crashes Please refer to the attached crash logs.</description></item><item><title>Use Source Code Control, even when working on your own</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/02/01/use-source-code-control-even-when-working-on-your-own/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 17:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/02/01/use-source-code-control-even-when-working-on-your-own/</guid><description>I use a source code control system (SCCS) from day one on all my projects, even when I am working alone. Here are some of the reasons why.
Backup I run a SCCS server on a separate computer, not my development box, so that all my brilliant code is stored safely on a second computer. If anything happens to my primary development box, no dramas, I can get the code back from the server.</description></item><item><title>Site Design</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/01/18/site-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/01/18/site-design/</guid><description>I wanted a site that was fast, minimalist, simple and focussed on the content. So I designed a web site with sidebars, navigation bars, more navigation in the footer, and lots of graphic elements. It looked great. But it was neither fast, nor simple and the content was hard to find. So, I redesigned it.
Fast I wanted the site to bring up the chosen page very quickly, especially since my hosting provider is not the speediest of all.</description></item></channel></rss>