<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Techie on Noverse</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/tags/techie/</link><description>Recent content in Techie on Noverse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 16:22:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noverse.github.io/tags/techie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Delivering Solutions: Corporate, Appliance or Hosted</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/01/21/delivering-solutions-corporate-appliance-or-hosted/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 16:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2011/01/21/delivering-solutions-corporate-appliance-or-hosted/</guid><description>I have just spent the past few weeks working on the initial design of a new product for Noverse. The question was how to deliver the solution to our customers. We could:
Install it on their infrastructure - lets call that the &amp;ldquo;Corporate Model&amp;rdquo; Deliver a prebuilt computer with the software on it - lets call that the &amp;ldquo;Appliance Model&amp;rdquo; Host it on our gear accessible over the internet - lets call it the &amp;ldquo;Hosted Model&amp;rdquo; Lets look at each in turn.</description></item><item><title>How to use software</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/09/09/how-to-use-software/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 13:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/09/09/how-to-use-software/</guid><description>I was having a discussion the other day about my next OS X application and the responses I got were that there was a free web way or a free command line way to do what my app will do, so why bother?
It got me thinking about how I use software, how other people use software, how people tell me how to use software and how I tell other people how to use software.</description></item><item><title>iPad Update - after almost a month traveling with it</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/05/15/ipad-update-after-almost-a-month-traveling-with-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2010 11:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/05/15/ipad-update-after-almost-a-month-traveling-with-it/</guid><description>I have now had the iPad for five weeks, three and a half of which were spent traveling through Eastern Europe with it as my only companion device (other than the iPhone 3GS). Short version, it&amp;rsquo;s brilliant. Long version, still brilliant.
On the trip:
The wifi issues that plagued me at home were never seen. When there was wifi available, that is. Most hotels had some kind of wifi available, but they charged an arm and a leg for it.</description></item><item><title>It's been one week since you looked at me</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/04/12/its-been-one-week-since-you-looked-at-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 10:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/04/12/its-been-one-week-since-you-looked-at-me/</guid><description>After a week with the iPad&amp;hellip;
I have read a few books on it. In fact, that&amp;rsquo;s where I have spent most of my time on it. The text is easy to read about three notches from smallest, but I need to dim the screen at night as it gets too bright. No eyestrain so far. I have made a few of my own documents into ePubs and it works great.</description></item><item><title>iPad First Impressions</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/04/04/ipad-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 12:32:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/blog/2010/04/04/ipad-first-impressions/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had an iPad now for 24 hours and these are my initial impressions of the device and its software.
Hardware It&amp;rsquo;s heavier than I expected, but feels nice and solid. I do seem to get tired holding it, but I guess my hands and arms will get used to it. The plasticky power switch, orientation lock and home button click sound and feel cheap. The screen is awesome. Bright, colorful, wide viewing angle and totally smudged by my fingerprints.</description></item></channel></rss>