<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Services on Noverse</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/services/</link><description>Recent content in Services on Noverse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 17:10:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noverse.github.io/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consulting Services</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/services/consulting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 17:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/services/consulting/</guid><description>Starting a business, starting a new line of business, or just trying to bring things up to date. With over 10 years in the finance industry and the 10 before that elsewhere, Noverse&amp;rsquo;s consulting services can help you in a myriad of ways, including:
Outsourced CTO: If you need a part-time Chief Technology Officer (CTO) to manage your technology team, look after your vendors and lead your technology strategy, Noverse can help.</description></item><item><title>Process and Training Services</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/services/process/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/services/process/</guid><description>Noverse&amp;rsquo;s process and training services provide you and your team with the skills and processes to run a better, more efficient, more responsive, leaner and sharper IT group. Services include:
Project Management: Our principal&amp;rsquo;s almost 20 years of active project management experience means than Noverse can manage your projects exceptionally well. Our training services can also show you how to manage your projects better. Learn how to plan, manage, organize and control your project, motivate your project team and satisfy your project&amp;rsquo;s customer.</description></item><item><title>Design Services</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/services/design/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 17:23:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/services/design/</guid><description>Traditionally, the software design process has been one of documenting how a requirement will be implemented in code. That definition misses the whole point of software design. True software design is about technical design (platform, architecture and workflow) and non-technical design (usability, user experience, and intuitiveness). Noverse&amp;rsquo;s product design services encompass both.
Technical design: Noverse can design the right platform to meet your business and software needs. Noverse will design a solid systems architecture to enable you to efficiently build and integrate your systems, scale your business and expand your competencies.</description></item><item><title>Development Services</title><link>https://noverse.github.io/services/development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 17:16:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.github.io/services/development/</guid><description>Software needs to get written. That&amp;rsquo;s where Noverse&amp;rsquo;s development services come in. Noverse produces software that is properly architected, robust, reliable, fast, scaleable, very maintainable, useable, matches the true needs of your business, looks great, is proven correct (especially in finance related applications), and is done right. Noverse uses an agile collaborative process to produce software, releasing lots of early builds to our clients to show progress and to improve collaboration.</description></item></channel></rss>