<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Noverse</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Noverse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 14:32:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noverse.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Did I Create as an Asset Manager CTO</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2022/09/12/what-did-i-create-as-an-asset-manager-cto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 14:32:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2022/09/12/what-did-i-create-as-an-asset-manager-cto/</guid><description>In this post, I am going to share what I built as CTO for the three Asset Managers I worked for over the past 22 years. I have created this page as a result of people asking for more information on what I actually did build, now that I have moved on from my third role.
In each case, these Asset Managers started as &amp;ldquo;green fields&amp;rdquo; startups. Using the technology I created for them, they grew from almost nothing to nearly billion dollar managers.</description></item><item><title>Hiltmonisms for Hedge Funds</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/12/hiltmonisms-for-hedge-funds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 14:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/12/hiltmonisms-for-hedge-funds/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span class="light">This post is another part in a series on &lt;strong>Hedge Fund Systems&lt;/strong>, a series of posts based on my experience in the design, implementation, issues and thoughts involved in crafting an end-to-end platform for a complex Hedge Fund.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the things I have been writing about on my personal blog over the past few years is a set of &lt;strong>Hiltmonisms&lt;/strong> - a bunch of maxims based on the collected experiences of my mentors and my own - on how to best create software and systems for businesses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this series on &lt;strong>Hedge Fund Systems&lt;/strong> I have referred to these maxims in passing. In this post I spend a bit of time looking at the &lt;strong>Hiltmonisms&lt;/strong> most applicable to Hedge Fund systems software design and development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Hedge Fund Technology Architecture</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/06/a-hedge-fund-technology-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 09:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/06/a-hedge-fund-technology-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span class="light">This post is another part in a series on &lt;a href="https://noverse.com/blog/categories/hedge-fund-systems/">Hedge Fund Systems&lt;/a>, a series of posts based on my experience in the design, implementation, issues and thoughts involved in crafting an end-to-end platform for a complex Hedge Fund.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a modified version of my original 2004 architecture plan for a Hedge Fund. See &lt;a href="https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/04/the-opportunity/">The Opportunity&lt;/a> for how it came about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post I cover the objectives of the architecture, walk through the architecture itself and provide an overview of &lt;code>The Greeks&lt;/code>, our implementation thereof.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Opportunity</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/04/the-opportunity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 16:48:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/04/the-opportunity/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span class="light">This post is the first part of a series on &lt;strong>Hedge Fund Systems&lt;/strong>, a series of posts based on my experience in the design, implementation, issues and thoughts involved in crafting an end-to-end platform for a complex Hedge Fund.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The year was 2004 and I was being offered a new job to be the Chief Technology Officer of a brand spanking new Hedge Fund that would trade &lt;em>everything&lt;/em> and launch within 6 months. Would I be interested in creating and managing a completely new technology platform to handle the end-to-end business needs of this new Wall Street firm?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would I? You bet I would!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the story of how I got the chance to design, create and grow a new financial business&amp;rsquo;s technology platform from scratch. And as amazing as it sounds, it all happened, it&amp;rsquo;s all true.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TimeToCall Released to the App Store</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/02/07/timetocall-released-to-the-app-store/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 09:42:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/02/07/timetocall-released-to-the-app-store/</guid><description>Noverse is very pleased to announce that TimeToCall v1.0 has shipped and can be downloaded on the App Store.
TimeToCall is a universal iPhone and iPad application to help you choose the best time to call people in other countries based on timezones.
Over 4000 locations to choose from Multiple Times to Call to lots of places Choose a Time to Call from different places Get a feel for when they are awake or asleep Play with Time to find the best Time to Call Available in Japanese as そっちは何時 Universal: iPhone or iPad (iOS 5.</description></item><item><title>Time To Call - Coming Soon</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/01/25/time-to-call-coming-soon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 17:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/01/25/time-to-call-coming-soon/</guid><description>“Ring Ring”
&amp;hellip;
“Hmmmm Hello”
&amp;hellip;
“Er Hi Mum”
&amp;hellip;
“Mum”
&amp;hellip;
“MUUUM”
&amp;hellip;
“Do you know what the time is?”
&amp;hellip;
“I know it’s after work in Sydney, but it’s 3AM here in New York”
&amp;hellip;
“Yes I was sleeping”
&amp;hellip;
“No, no, I’m awake now”
&amp;hellip;
“Just please check the time before you call”
Never know when is the best time to call people overseas?
TimeToCall is coming soon for the iPhone and iPad.</description></item><item><title>Hit by a Bus</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/01/14/hit-by-a-bus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 12:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/01/14/hit-by-a-bus/</guid><description>What would happen to my clients and my products if I got hit by a bus?
It’s a fair question given that I am an indie, and not part of a large company full of backup resources. These are things my clients do worry about, and a question all indies need to be able to answer.
Well, firstly, if I am going to get “taken out”, I’d prefer something better than a dirty old MTA bus.</description></item><item><title>Thank You for 2012</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/12/29/thank-you-for-2012/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 11:42:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/12/29/thank-you-for-2012/</guid><description>We at Noverse wish to thank all our wonderful clients and partners for such a brilliant third year in business. Unfortunately, most of our clients prefer to remain private, as in:
The first rule of Fight Club is: You do not talk about Fight Club.
The second rule of Fight Club is: You do not talk about Fight Club.
No matter, you know who you are.
Thank you for taking a chance on a growing business to service your needs.</description></item><item><title>Doing Software Demos Right</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/10/16/doing-software-demos-right/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 20:09:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/10/16/doing-software-demos-right/</guid><description>Over the past few years, I have been regularly demonstrating the huge complex end-to-end software platform that I developed in my last hedge fund. Before that, as a CTO, I sat through hundreds of software demonstrations.
If you have complex software that requires a demo, and if you are going to demo it, here are some software demo do’s and don’ts that I apply in my demos to others, and expect in demos to me</description></item><item><title>The Hedge Fund CTO Role</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/10/05/the-hedge-fund-cto-role/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 13:29:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/10/05/the-hedge-fund-cto-role/</guid><description>In this article, I intend to describe what a Chief Technology Officer does for an Asset Manager. Its not a comprehensive list, but will give you a feel for what I used to do in my previous jobs. I created this document as part of a presentation to a client and thought it may be useful to publish parts of it.
At a very high level, the CTO’s primary job is to make sure that the company’s technology strategy serves it’s business strategy.</description></item><item><title>Kifu v1.0 Released</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/07/12/kifu-v1-dot-0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 15:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/07/12/kifu-v1-dot-0-released/</guid><description>Noverse, via the The Shukai Company LLC, is very pleased to announce that Kifu v1.0.0 has shipped. And our first customers are already happily using Kifu in production. We want to thank all our beta testers and beta clients for testing Kifu and helping us make such a great product.
But we&amp;rsquo;re not stopping or even slowing down. We have the core platform, and we know it works. We also have many, many ideas and features we wish to add to help you maximize the value you get from Kifu in your small non-profit.</description></item><item><title>How to write a good bug report</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/06/15/how-to-write-a-good-bug-report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 11:57:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/06/15/how-to-write-a-good-bug-report/</guid><description>Software has bugs, yes, even ours. Since programmers are human, and humans make mistakes, ergo bugs. When you come across a bug in our software, or anyone else&amp;rsquo;s for that matter, you need to email in a bug report. The developer can use this to identify the problem, replicate the problem and fix it.
But most of the time, we developers find submitted bug reports to be incomprehensible. This is because the submitter has no idea what we need, how to communicate with us and how to write one of these bug report things.</description></item><item><title>Almost Shipping</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/03/24/almost-shipping/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 15:25:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/03/24/almost-shipping/</guid><description>After a year of discussions, planning, designing, programming, testing and making it happen, we&amp;rsquo;re about to ship the 1.0 version of Kifu.
But almost shipping is not the same as shipping.
The product is feature complete for version 1.0. It was a hard road getting here, and even harder to say no to features that would have delayed shipping. But it&amp;rsquo;s done, its almost shipping.
Almost shipping are where you are when there are still hundreds of small and sometimes large details that need to be right before you truly ship a web app.</description></item><item><title>Presenting a Professional Indie Image</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/03/05/presenting-a-professional-indie-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 11:31:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/03/05/presenting-a-professional-indie-image/</guid><description>As my hiltmon.com blog takes off, I am starting to get emails from indie developers promoting their wares. This is great, I love getting them, looking at new products and helping out where I can. But many of them fail on the basics of presenting themselves as the professionals they are.
In this article, I will present a checklist of all the things you need as an indie to present yourself to strangers via email with some credibility.</description></item><item><title>End of Life - Sights to See and Emergency List</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/02/12/end-of-life-sights-to-see-and-emergency-list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 21:10:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/02/12/end-of-life-sights-to-see-and-emergency-list/</guid><description>Noverse is sad to announce that we have taken down Emergency List and Sights to See from the iPhone App Store.
What? Really? Why? These apps were developed two years ago, for old versions of the iPhone, and no longer represent the best we can do. We were learning iOS at the time, did not have access to the right designers and did the best we could back then. It got us the business we did the last 2 years.</description></item><item><title>Moving to Hiltmon.com</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/12/27/hiltmon-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 09:04:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/12/27/hiltmon-com/</guid><description>You may have noticed less activity on this site. Or not. I have consolidated all my old blogs, and begun writing a more controversial and wide ranging blog at my personal domain https://hiltmon.com. Expect that one to get new articles more frequently and on a wider range of subjects. I am not sure what to do about this blog yet, so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it up for now. But check out https://hiltmon.</description></item><item><title>Get it Brilliant</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/09/17/get-it-brilliant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 13:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/09/17/get-it-brilliant/</guid><description>When it comes to software, there should be no such thing as &amp;lsquo;good enough&amp;rsquo; software. Yet most software fits this bill, it does something &amp;lsquo;good enough&amp;rsquo; to get the work done or even sell. Even though the user has to jump through hoops to do so, or create workarounds to make the whole thing work.
At Noverse, we don&amp;rsquo;t make &amp;lsquo;good enough&amp;rsquo; software. Our products must be brilliant, they must be flexible, they must be proven correct, they must get the job done without workarounds, they must be fast and easy to use, they must be amazing.</description></item><item><title>Alpha Testing</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/07/31/alpha-testing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 15:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/07/31/alpha-testing/</guid><description>Everybody talks about Beta testing, unit testing and integration testing, but there is little on Alpha testing out there. At Noverse, we do them all.
What is Alpha Testing? If you follow the Wikipedia definition, Alpha testing happens when the product is incomplete and yet still handed over to a testing team inside the organization. And Beta testing happens when the customer gets to test pre-release versions.
For us, a small indie developer, we have no separate testing or Q&amp;amp;A team, so our Alpha testing is done with our customers as well.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Customers Engaged Early</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/05/13/keeping-customers-engaged-early/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 17:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/05/13/keeping-customers-engaged-early/</guid><description>The early stages of a software development project are brilliant for a designer/developer and painful for a customer. For the developer, the challenge of design, the joy of programming the core functionality, and the absolute bliss you get from making something great keeps the developer engaged. The customer sits and waits. And waits.
Traditionally, that wait lasts a long time, all the way until Alpha builds are available. Even with agile programming techniques, there really isn&amp;rsquo;t much to show the customer during the early stages.</description></item><item><title>Time and Material Contracts, with a Process</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/04/05/time-and-material-contracts-with-a-process/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 11:48:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/04/05/time-and-material-contracts-with-a-process/</guid><description>Call in a contractor to fix a hole in your roof. On a fixed price contract, they will rush to the roof, staple a plastic sheet over the hole and be done in 10 minutes. On a time and materials contract, they will wait for permission to go onto the roof, and sit up there for hours texting their mates, then staple the plastic sheet. On an equity share contract, they will move in, and place a bucket under the hole.</description></item><item><title>Reviews are not Support Requests</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/03/21/reviews-are-not-support-requests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 11:13:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/03/21/reviews-are-not-support-requests/</guid><description>One of the biggest things missing in the iTunes App Store is the ability for the developer of an app to respond to complaints raised in the reviews section of their app.
We all know that the purpose of a review is to document an honest experience with a product. We all also should know that every app on the store has a support link, where customers are supposed to go to report any issues, errors or problems, or to ask questions of the developer.</description></item><item><title>To a nail, everything looks like a hammer</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/03/05/to-a-nail-everything-looks-like-a-hammer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 10:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/03/05/to-a-nail-everything-looks-like-a-hammer/</guid><description>One of the most common scenarios I see is companies using Excel to run their core business. Whenever a new report is needed, new analysis, new form, data conversion, no matter the task, they turn to Excel. They make everything look like a nail, and the only tool they understand is Excel, so they use it like a hammer. The result? Manual processes, inconsistent data, key-person dependencies, inflexibility, pain and suffering.</description></item><item><title>Delivering Solutions: Corporate, Appliance or Hosted</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/01/21/delivering-solutions-corporate-appliance-or-hosted/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 16:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/01/21/delivering-solutions-corporate-appliance-or-hosted/</guid><description>I have just spent the past few weeks working on the initial design of a new product for Noverse. The question was how to deliver the solution to our customers. We could:
Install it on their infrastructure - lets call that the &amp;ldquo;Corporate Model&amp;rdquo; Deliver a prebuilt computer with the software on it - lets call that the &amp;ldquo;Appliance Model&amp;rdquo; Host it on our gear accessible over the internet - lets call it the &amp;ldquo;Hosted Model&amp;rdquo; Lets look at each in turn.</description></item><item><title>It takes a Software Designer</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/16/it-takes-a-software-designer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 18:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/16/it-takes-a-software-designer/</guid><description>In many of my articles, I talk about the Software Designer, I even call myself one. But what does this mythical person do? Are they a graphics designer? An architect? A consultant?
A software designer is an individual who has the vision, passion, communication, understanding, flexibility and process to generate software form; and make the necessary decisions about what, when, where and how in development.
Note that the designer does not necessarily conceptualize the idea.</description></item><item><title>A Few Good Men</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/11/a-few-good-men/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 11:32:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/11/a-few-good-men/</guid><description>With apologies to the movie A Few Good Men, 1992, directed by Rob Reiner.
The right team size for software development. How many people does it take to develop a Software Product? How big a team will I need to create to tools for my business? I need to migrate this legacy software to a new platform, how many programmers will I need?
These are common questions asked of CTO&amp;rsquo;s, IT Consultants, startups, techies and, of course, me.</description></item><item><title>How much does it cost to develop an iPhone application?</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/01/how-much-does-it-cost-to-develop-an-iphone-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 13:59:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/01/how-much-does-it-cost-to-develop-an-iphone-application/</guid><description>This question was asked, and answered, on stackoverflow.com 2 years ago, and has been viewed almost 200,000 times. I was one of the people who answered the question (click here).
There are three components in almost every iPhone app: a server component, a design component and an app component.
Server Component The server component of an iPhone app usually takes the most effort and chews up the majority of the budget.</description></item><item><title>Waterfall Waterfail</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/10/28/waterfall-waterfail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 01:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/10/28/waterfall-waterfail/</guid><description>The waterfall model for software development has gone the way of the dodo (and did so at about the same time). Yet this newly minted indie developer often gets requests for proposals that follow this model, fixed-time, fixed-process and fixed-price.
I instantly and politely decline these requests.
I don&amp;rsquo;t ever want to decline work, and when I set up this business, I planned to say yes to every potential client and service them as best as possible.</description></item><item><title>Sprint Coding</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/10/15/sprint-coding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 13:42:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/10/15/sprint-coding/</guid><description>Sprint Coding is the process whereby a skilled programmer busts out a quality application in record time.
Its not easy. Fast coding means faster bugs. Quick coding means rotten quality. Rapid development means architecture is ignored. Cowboy coding produces unmaintainable code. In short, I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend it.
But, my dear padawan, it is do-able under the right circumstances. Rare circumstances. Recommend this, I do not.
Scenario, this is. A client called up at the beginning of October and asked if I could produce an iPhone app for them.</description></item><item><title>Sights to See iPad Version Progress, Part 1</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/09/30/sights-to-see-ipad-version-progress-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 17:04:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/09/30/sights-to-see-ipad-version-progress-part-1/</guid><description>The iPad version of Sights to See is coming along nicely. All the views have been strung together and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to work on the details and aesthetics.
Here are a few screenshots to whet your appetite.
When you start the app, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a world map with all your guides on it. I am also experimenting with a &amp;rsquo;tag cloud&amp;quot; approach to help you jump to a guide quickly, but it may not make it into the final product.</description></item><item><title>How to use software</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/09/09/how-to-use-software/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 13:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/09/09/how-to-use-software/</guid><description>I was having a discussion the other day about my next OS X application and the responses I got were that there was a free web way or a free command line way to do what my app will do, so why bother?
It got me thinking about how I use software, how other people use software, how people tell me how to use software and how I tell other people how to use software.</description></item><item><title>The post shipping, app store review blues</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/08/20/the-post-shipping-app-store-review-blues/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/08/20/the-post-shipping-app-store-review-blues/</guid><description>Real programmers ship. I did, ten days ago, into the App Store review process. And now I have the postnatal shipping blues.
The blues come from two sources, shipping and waiting.
shipping blues The first version of an application always ships, if you do it right, with the critical core features working, one or two bells and whistles to make it fun and nothing else. Do any more, and you&amp;rsquo;ll never ship.</description></item><item><title>The price of Sights to See</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/08/11/the-price-of-sights-to-see/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 11:49:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/08/11/the-price-of-sights-to-see/</guid><description>Choosing a price for your software is hard. Choosing the right price is even harder.
For Sights to See, I will release it at $9.99.
Let the wailing begin!
Customer value proposition From a customer&amp;rsquo;s perspective the value proposition is easy to figure out.
If the customer buys a paper guide book, it costs about $20.00 from Amazon. The paper guide book is limited to only the places in it, weighs a lot, is hard to navigate and to navigate with, and is usually out of date.</description></item><item><title>How to deal with an iPhone crash report, a better way</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/08/10/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report-a-better-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 11:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/08/10/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report-a-better-way/</guid><description>There is an easier way to deal with an iPhone crash report than in my previous article How to deal with an iPhone crash report. And here it is.
Before you release the app Run a Build and Archive in Xcode, making sure that the version you are building is the one you are sending out (beta release or final release, properly code signed).
Xcode builds the app, the places the app, its dSYM file, a plist and the ipa file in ~/Library/Mobiledevice/Archived Applications/&amp;lt;UUID&amp;gt;/ where it can be found and managed by Organizer and by spotlight.</description></item><item><title>Hanging out my shingle</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/31/hanging-out-my-shingle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 17:01:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/31/hanging-out-my-shingle/</guid><description>I have freed up enough of my time to be able to offer my skills as technology strategist, systems architect, software designer, consultant, public speaker, programmer and super software sage for hire.
I have 21 years of experience, started out as a programmer, grew into a complex project manager, and landed up as Chief Technology Officer (and number one programming guru) at two successful and very complex hedge funds. 21 years of experience makes me a great programmer, accomplished systems architect and seasoned manager.</description></item><item><title>Beta testing is hard, but oh so worth it</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/31/beta-testing-is-hard-but-oh-so-worth-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 13:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/31/beta-testing-is-hard-but-oh-so-worth-it/</guid><description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve built the next killer app, and it looks and feels and works exactly how you dreamed, designed, planned and sweated to make it. Even the non-programming stuff is as brilliant as you can make it, the web site, the artwork, the documentation and the press goodies. As far as you are concerned, it&amp;rsquo;s ready to ship - and real developers ship after all.
Not so fast, bucakaroo! Best to beta test first.</description></item><item><title>Testing the new Web Design</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/16/testing-the-new-web-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 10:50:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/16/testing-the-new-web-design/</guid><description>I decided to revamp the noverse.com website before it became too complex. The original site had too many pages, and tons of html was being repeated. Every change had to be made in too many places, and as a developer, that violates the rules.
So, I switched from HTML/CSS to PHP-HTML/CSS. Easy. The only PHP I am using is to include common blocks of code, like the navigation bar, sidebar and footer.</description></item><item><title>One Two Four Eight - The Indie Developer's Life</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/05/24/one-two-four-eight-the-indie-developers-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 12:17:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/05/24/one-two-four-eight-the-indie-developers-life/</guid><description>Instructions: For timespan, insert day, week, month, year, eon or parsec. Use the same timespan for each section.
Build Version 1.0 Core features only, focus on the primary need
One timespan to write the core feature and prove the application.
Two timespans to add the minimum and absolutely necessary features to give the application Version 1.0 functionality and no more.
Four timespans to get it stable, fast and mostly bug free.</description></item><item><title>App Sales, free vs 99c</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/05/15/app-sales-free-vs-99c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2010 11:57:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/05/15/app-sales-free-vs-99c/</guid><description>I ran a test while on vacation. For the 3.5 weeks I was away, I changed the price of Emergency List from free to 99c to see how this would affect sales.
It did.
A lot.
Before the price change, I had daily sales in the tens of units.
After the price change, I had three sales in 3.5 weeks. Zero sales every other day.
So I set the price back to zero two days ago, just to see what would happen.</description></item><item><title>iPad Update - after almost a month traveling with it</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/05/15/ipad-update-after-almost-a-month-traveling-with-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2010 11:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/05/15/ipad-update-after-almost-a-month-traveling-with-it/</guid><description>I have now had the iPad for five weeks, three and a half of which were spent traveling through Eastern Europe with it as my only companion device (other than the iPhone 3GS). Short version, it&amp;rsquo;s brilliant. Long version, still brilliant.
On the trip:
The wifi issues that plagued me at home were never seen. When there was wifi available, that is. Most hotels had some kind of wifi available, but they charged an arm and a leg for it.</description></item><item><title>It's been one week since you looked at me</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/04/12/its-been-one-week-since-you-looked-at-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 10:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/04/12/its-been-one-week-since-you-looked-at-me/</guid><description>After a week with the iPad&amp;hellip;
I have read a few books on it. In fact, that&amp;rsquo;s where I have spent most of my time on it. The text is easy to read about three notches from smallest, but I need to dim the screen at night as it gets too bright. No eyestrain so far. I have made a few of my own documents into ePubs and it works great.</description></item><item><title>iPad First Impressions</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/04/04/ipad-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 12:32:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/04/04/ipad-first-impressions/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had an iPad now for 24 hours and these are my initial impressions of the device and its software.
Hardware It&amp;rsquo;s heavier than I expected, but feels nice and solid. I do seem to get tired holding it, but I guess my hands and arms will get used to it. The plasticky power switch, orientation lock and home button click sound and feel cheap. The screen is awesome. Bright, colorful, wide viewing angle and totally smudged by my fingerprints.</description></item><item><title>Replacing the Address Book Picker</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/11/replacing-the-address-book-picker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 12:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/11/replacing-the-address-book-picker/</guid><description>In the first release of Emergency List, I used the default ABPeoplePickerNavigationController to allow users to add emergency contacts from their iPhone Address Book. Real users found it confusing, so I wrote my own.
What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with the Apple implementation? The requirement is for the user to pick a phone number for a contact.
The implementation requires you to launch an address book picker which displays a list of contact names - just the names and nothing else.</description></item><item><title>How to deal with an iPhone crash report</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/03/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 22:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/03/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report/</guid><description>Kudos to the app review team at Apple, they found a crasher in the update to Emergency List that I recently submitted. They even took the time to step through and document what they did exactly to reproduce the error.
From their email:
1. Launch app connected to a network 2. Tap Emergency List 3. Tap the Add button 4. Tap Add from Address Book 5. App crashes Please refer to the attached crash logs.</description></item><item><title>Emergency List - Finishing Touches</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/02/emergency-list-finishing-touches/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 17:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/02/emergency-list-finishing-touches/</guid><description>Part 6 in the continuing the story of my first iPhone application as an Indie Developer, starting with the requirements, the design, first iteration, updated UI and last week&amp;rsquo;s internals and bells. In short, I am documenting all the successes and failures in developing my first iPhone app.
The Web I added the following pages to noverse.com:
Created a Products Page. All it does is list my (currently one and only) iPhone app.</description></item><item><title>Emergency Numbers - Internals and Bells</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/19/emergency-numbers-internals-and-bells/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 17:53:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/19/emergency-numbers-internals-and-bells/</guid><description>Part 5 in the continuing the story of my first iPhone application as an Indie Developer, starting with the requirements, the design, first iteration and last week&amp;rsquo;s updated UI. In short, I am documenting all the successes and failures in developing my first iPhone app.
Internals I spent one day rejigging the data model for the app, without changing the data file format. The original model had methods for each and every attribute of an emergency contact, such as currentContactName, currentContactIcon and setCurrentContactNumber.</description></item><item><title>Emergency Numbers - Updated UI</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/12/emergency-numbers-updated-ui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 14:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/12/emergency-numbers-updated-ui/</guid><description>Part 4 in the continuing the story of my first iPhone application as an Indie Developer, starting with the requirements, the design and last week&amp;rsquo;s first iteration. In short, I am documenting all the successes and failures in developing my first iPhone app.
UI Updates The best way to read this article is to open the previous article in another window so you can see the UI changes.
Favorites I was very unhappy with the look and feel of the favorites page.</description></item><item><title>Emergency Numbers - Core Functionality in One Week</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/07/emergency-numbers-core-functionality-in-one-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 12:28:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/07/emergency-numbers-core-functionality-in-one-week/</guid><description>Continuing the story of my first iPhone application as an Indie Developer, starting with why in Becoming Better, the requirements in First Application - Emergency List and last week&amp;rsquo;s First Draft Application Design - Emergency List. In short, I am documenting all the successes and failures in developing my first iPhone app.
After One Week&amp;rsquo;s Coding After a week of coding, the following functionality has been developed. All screenshots are taken from my development iPod Touch, they are not mockups.</description></item><item><title>Use Source Code Control, even when working on your own</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/01/use-source-code-control-even-when-working-on-your-own/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 17:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/01/use-source-code-control-even-when-working-on-your-own/</guid><description>I use a source code control system (SCCS) from day one on all my projects, even when I am working alone. Here are some of the reasons why.
Backup I run a SCCS server on a separate computer, not my development box, so that all my brilliant code is stored safely on a second computer. If anything happens to my primary development box, no dramas, I can get the code back from the server.</description></item><item><title>What is a Software Designer?</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/29/what-is-a-software-designer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/29/what-is-a-software-designer/</guid><description>I call myself a Software Designer. So should you. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
If we ignore the dictionary and follow colloquial use, we could be called a:
Programmer - someone who writes software code. Unfortunately, it is implied that programmers do not design the software, nor do they decide what to do next or how things will work, they merely translate a limited set of requirements or a small part of the design into code.</description></item><item><title>First Draft Application Design - Emergency List</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/25/first-draft-application-design-emergency-list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 15:21:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/25/first-draft-application-design-emergency-list/</guid><description>We know what I want to develop, see The First Application - Emergency List. As its an iPhone app, the first step is to draw up the user interface. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a mockup of the interface and some of the thinking behind it.
The Interface - Favorites The first requirement is that it should take only two taps to call an emergency number, tap once to launch the app, tap again to call the emergency number.</description></item><item><title>The First Application - Emergency List</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/20/the-first-application-emergency-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 12:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/20/the-first-application-emergency-list/</guid><description>Most people I know, especially the elderly and those with kids, have a piece of paper taped to their landline phones containing a list of emergency or key contact numbers. That way, when needed, the number needed is easily found, and anyone can dial it.
I intend to create an iPhone application to do this.
Problems it will Solve Calling the right number in an emergency very very quickly without having to search for it Finding the necessary supporting information when making an emergency call Sharing the list and keeping it up to date Key Features and Benefits Feature 1: Two taps to call the top emergency contacts - I&amp;rsquo;d like the top 5 emergency numbers to be presented on startup, allowing the user to tap to launch the app, then tap an entry to dial.</description></item><item><title>Site Design</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/18/site-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/18/site-design/</guid><description>I wanted a site that was fast, minimalist, simple and focussed on the content. So I designed a web site with sidebars, navigation bars, more navigation in the footer, and lots of graphic elements. It looked great. But it was neither fast, nor simple and the content was hard to find. So, I redesigned it.
Fast I wanted the site to bring up the chosen page very quickly, especially since my hosting provider is not the speediest of all.</description></item><item><title>Becoming Better</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/18/becoming-better/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 17:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/18/becoming-better/</guid><description>I created this site and its blog for two purposes, to document the thoughts and experiences of a new indie application developer and to share the lessons I have learned designing and developing software over the past 20 years. At first glance, these two so not seem to intersect.
Being an Indie Developer It is my intention to design and develop a set of Macintosh and iPhone based applications that are truly useful to people, well designed, seamlessly integrated, look brilliant and most importantly do what they are supposed to do best.</description></item></channel></rss>