<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Designer on Noverse</title><link>https://noverse.com/tags/software-designer/</link><description>Recent content in Software Designer on Noverse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 21:10:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noverse.com/tags/software-designer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>End of Life - Sights to See and Emergency List</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/02/12/end-of-life-sights-to-see-and-emergency-list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 21:10:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2012/02/12/end-of-life-sights-to-see-and-emergency-list/</guid><description>Noverse is sad to announce that we have taken down Emergency List and Sights to See from the iPhone App Store.
What? Really? Why? These apps were developed two years ago, for old versions of the iPhone, and no longer represent the best we can do. We were learning iOS at the time, did not have access to the right designers and did the best we could back then. It got us the business we did the last 2 years.</description></item><item><title>Get it Brilliant</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/09/17/get-it-brilliant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 13:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/09/17/get-it-brilliant/</guid><description>When it comes to software, there should be no such thing as &amp;lsquo;good enough&amp;rsquo; software. Yet most software fits this bill, it does something &amp;lsquo;good enough&amp;rsquo; to get the work done or even sell. Even though the user has to jump through hoops to do so, or create workarounds to make the whole thing work.
At Noverse, we don&amp;rsquo;t make &amp;lsquo;good enough&amp;rsquo; software. Our products must be brilliant, they must be flexible, they must be proven correct, they must get the job done without workarounds, they must be fast and easy to use, they must be amazing.</description></item><item><title>Alpha Testing</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/07/31/alpha-testing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 15:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/07/31/alpha-testing/</guid><description>Everybody talks about Beta testing, unit testing and integration testing, but there is little on Alpha testing out there. At Noverse, we do them all.
What is Alpha Testing? If you follow the Wikipedia definition, Alpha testing happens when the product is incomplete and yet still handed over to a testing team inside the organization. And Beta testing happens when the customer gets to test pre-release versions.
For us, a small indie developer, we have no separate testing or Q&amp;amp;A team, so our Alpha testing is done with our customers as well.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Customers Engaged Early</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/05/13/keeping-customers-engaged-early/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 17:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/05/13/keeping-customers-engaged-early/</guid><description>The early stages of a software development project are brilliant for a designer/developer and painful for a customer. For the developer, the challenge of design, the joy of programming the core functionality, and the absolute bliss you get from making something great keeps the developer engaged. The customer sits and waits. And waits.
Traditionally, that wait lasts a long time, all the way until Alpha builds are available. Even with agile programming techniques, there really isn&amp;rsquo;t much to show the customer during the early stages.</description></item><item><title>To a nail, everything looks like a hammer</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/03/05/to-a-nail-everything-looks-like-a-hammer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 10:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/03/05/to-a-nail-everything-looks-like-a-hammer/</guid><description>One of the most common scenarios I see is companies using Excel to run their core business. Whenever a new report is needed, new analysis, new form, data conversion, no matter the task, they turn to Excel. They make everything look like a nail, and the only tool they understand is Excel, so they use it like a hammer. The result? Manual processes, inconsistent data, key-person dependencies, inflexibility, pain and suffering.</description></item><item><title>Delivering Solutions: Corporate, Appliance or Hosted</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/01/21/delivering-solutions-corporate-appliance-or-hosted/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 16:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2011/01/21/delivering-solutions-corporate-appliance-or-hosted/</guid><description>I have just spent the past few weeks working on the initial design of a new product for Noverse. The question was how to deliver the solution to our customers. We could:
Install it on their infrastructure - lets call that the &amp;ldquo;Corporate Model&amp;rdquo; Deliver a prebuilt computer with the software on it - lets call that the &amp;ldquo;Appliance Model&amp;rdquo; Host it on our gear accessible over the internet - lets call it the &amp;ldquo;Hosted Model&amp;rdquo; Lets look at each in turn.</description></item><item><title>It takes a Software Designer</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/16/it-takes-a-software-designer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 18:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/16/it-takes-a-software-designer/</guid><description>In many of my articles, I talk about the Software Designer, I even call myself one. But what does this mythical person do? Are they a graphics designer? An architect? A consultant?
A software designer is an individual who has the vision, passion, communication, understanding, flexibility and process to generate software form; and make the necessary decisions about what, when, where and how in development.
Note that the designer does not necessarily conceptualize the idea.</description></item><item><title>A Few Good Men</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/11/a-few-good-men/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 11:32:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/11/a-few-good-men/</guid><description>With apologies to the movie A Few Good Men, 1992, directed by Rob Reiner.
The right team size for software development. How many people does it take to develop a Software Product? How big a team will I need to create to tools for my business? I need to migrate this legacy software to a new platform, how many programmers will I need?
These are common questions asked of CTO&amp;rsquo;s, IT Consultants, startups, techies and, of course, me.</description></item><item><title>How much does it cost to develop an iPhone application?</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/01/how-much-does-it-cost-to-develop-an-iphone-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 13:59:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/12/01/how-much-does-it-cost-to-develop-an-iphone-application/</guid><description>This question was asked, and answered, on stackoverflow.com 2 years ago, and has been viewed almost 200,000 times. I was one of the people who answered the question (click here).
There are three components in almost every iPhone app: a server component, a design component and an app component.
Server Component The server component of an iPhone app usually takes the most effort and chews up the majority of the budget.</description></item><item><title>Sprint Coding</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/10/15/sprint-coding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 13:42:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/10/15/sprint-coding/</guid><description>Sprint Coding is the process whereby a skilled programmer busts out a quality application in record time.
Its not easy. Fast coding means faster bugs. Quick coding means rotten quality. Rapid development means architecture is ignored. Cowboy coding produces unmaintainable code. In short, I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend it.
But, my dear padawan, it is do-able under the right circumstances. Rare circumstances. Recommend this, I do not.
Scenario, this is. A client called up at the beginning of October and asked if I could produce an iPhone app for them.</description></item><item><title>Sights to See iPad Version Progress, Part 1</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/09/30/sights-to-see-ipad-version-progress-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 17:04:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/09/30/sights-to-see-ipad-version-progress-part-1/</guid><description>The iPad version of Sights to See is coming along nicely. All the views have been strung together and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to work on the details and aesthetics.
Here are a few screenshots to whet your appetite.
When you start the app, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a world map with all your guides on it. I am also experimenting with a &amp;rsquo;tag cloud&amp;quot; approach to help you jump to a guide quickly, but it may not make it into the final product.</description></item><item><title>How to use software</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/09/09/how-to-use-software/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 13:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/09/09/how-to-use-software/</guid><description>I was having a discussion the other day about my next OS X application and the responses I got were that there was a free web way or a free command line way to do what my app will do, so why bother?
It got me thinking about how I use software, how other people use software, how people tell me how to use software and how I tell other people how to use software.</description></item><item><title>How to deal with an iPhone crash report, a better way</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/08/10/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report-a-better-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 11:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/08/10/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report-a-better-way/</guid><description>There is an easier way to deal with an iPhone crash report than in my previous article How to deal with an iPhone crash report. And here it is.
Before you release the app Run a Build and Archive in Xcode, making sure that the version you are building is the one you are sending out (beta release or final release, properly code signed).
Xcode builds the app, the places the app, its dSYM file, a plist and the ipa file in ~/Library/Mobiledevice/Archived Applications/&amp;lt;UUID&amp;gt;/ where it can be found and managed by Organizer and by spotlight.</description></item><item><title>Hanging out my shingle</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/31/hanging-out-my-shingle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 17:01:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/31/hanging-out-my-shingle/</guid><description>I have freed up enough of my time to be able to offer my skills as technology strategist, systems architect, software designer, consultant, public speaker, programmer and super software sage for hire.
I have 21 years of experience, started out as a programmer, grew into a complex project manager, and landed up as Chief Technology Officer (and number one programming guru) at two successful and very complex hedge funds. 21 years of experience makes me a great programmer, accomplished systems architect and seasoned manager.</description></item><item><title>Beta testing is hard, but oh so worth it</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/31/beta-testing-is-hard-but-oh-so-worth-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 13:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/07/31/beta-testing-is-hard-but-oh-so-worth-it/</guid><description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve built the next killer app, and it looks and feels and works exactly how you dreamed, designed, planned and sweated to make it. Even the non-programming stuff is as brilliant as you can make it, the web site, the artwork, the documentation and the press goodies. As far as you are concerned, it&amp;rsquo;s ready to ship - and real developers ship after all.
Not so fast, bucakaroo! Best to beta test first.</description></item><item><title>One Two Four Eight - The Indie Developer's Life</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/05/24/one-two-four-eight-the-indie-developers-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 12:17:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/05/24/one-two-four-eight-the-indie-developers-life/</guid><description>Instructions: For timespan, insert day, week, month, year, eon or parsec. Use the same timespan for each section.
Build Version 1.0 Core features only, focus on the primary need
One timespan to write the core feature and prove the application.
Two timespans to add the minimum and absolutely necessary features to give the application Version 1.0 functionality and no more.
Four timespans to get it stable, fast and mostly bug free.</description></item><item><title>Replacing the Address Book Picker</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/11/replacing-the-address-book-picker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 12:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/11/replacing-the-address-book-picker/</guid><description>In the first release of Emergency List, I used the default ABPeoplePickerNavigationController to allow users to add emergency contacts from their iPhone Address Book. Real users found it confusing, so I wrote my own.
What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with the Apple implementation? The requirement is for the user to pick a phone number for a contact.
The implementation requires you to launch an address book picker which displays a list of contact names - just the names and nothing else.</description></item><item><title>How to deal with an iPhone crash report</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/03/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 22:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/03/how-to-deal-with-an-iphone-crash-report/</guid><description>Kudos to the app review team at Apple, they found a crasher in the update to Emergency List that I recently submitted. They even took the time to step through and document what they did exactly to reproduce the error.
From their email:
1. Launch app connected to a network 2. Tap Emergency List 3. Tap the Add button 4. Tap Add from Address Book 5. App crashes Please refer to the attached crash logs.</description></item><item><title>Emergency List - Finishing Touches</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/02/emergency-list-finishing-touches/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 17:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/03/02/emergency-list-finishing-touches/</guid><description>Part 6 in the continuing the story of my first iPhone application as an Indie Developer, starting with the requirements, the design, first iteration, updated UI and last week&amp;rsquo;s internals and bells. In short, I am documenting all the successes and failures in developing my first iPhone app.
The Web I added the following pages to noverse.com:
Created a Products Page. All it does is list my (currently one and only) iPhone app.</description></item><item><title>Emergency Numbers - Internals and Bells</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/19/emergency-numbers-internals-and-bells/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 17:53:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/19/emergency-numbers-internals-and-bells/</guid><description>Part 5 in the continuing the story of my first iPhone application as an Indie Developer, starting with the requirements, the design, first iteration and last week&amp;rsquo;s updated UI. In short, I am documenting all the successes and failures in developing my first iPhone app.
Internals I spent one day rejigging the data model for the app, without changing the data file format. The original model had methods for each and every attribute of an emergency contact, such as currentContactName, currentContactIcon and setCurrentContactNumber.</description></item><item><title>Emergency Numbers - Updated UI</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/12/emergency-numbers-updated-ui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 14:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/12/emergency-numbers-updated-ui/</guid><description>Part 4 in the continuing the story of my first iPhone application as an Indie Developer, starting with the requirements, the design and last week&amp;rsquo;s first iteration. In short, I am documenting all the successes and failures in developing my first iPhone app.
UI Updates The best way to read this article is to open the previous article in another window so you can see the UI changes.
Favorites I was very unhappy with the look and feel of the favorites page.</description></item><item><title>Emergency Numbers - Core Functionality in One Week</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/07/emergency-numbers-core-functionality-in-one-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 12:28:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/02/07/emergency-numbers-core-functionality-in-one-week/</guid><description>Continuing the story of my first iPhone application as an Indie Developer, starting with why in Becoming Better, the requirements in First Application - Emergency List and last week&amp;rsquo;s First Draft Application Design - Emergency List. In short, I am documenting all the successes and failures in developing my first iPhone app.
After One Week&amp;rsquo;s Coding After a week of coding, the following functionality has been developed. All screenshots are taken from my development iPod Touch, they are not mockups.</description></item><item><title>What is a Software Designer?</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/29/what-is-a-software-designer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/29/what-is-a-software-designer/</guid><description>I call myself a Software Designer. So should you. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
If we ignore the dictionary and follow colloquial use, we could be called a:
Programmer - someone who writes software code. Unfortunately, it is implied that programmers do not design the software, nor do they decide what to do next or how things will work, they merely translate a limited set of requirements or a small part of the design into code.</description></item><item><title>Becoming Better</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/18/becoming-better/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 17:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2010/01/18/becoming-better/</guid><description>I created this site and its blog for two purposes, to document the thoughts and experiences of a new indie application developer and to share the lessons I have learned designing and developing software over the past 20 years. At first glance, these two so not seem to intersect.
Being an Indie Developer It is my intention to design and develop a set of Macintosh and iPhone based applications that are truly useful to people, well designed, seamlessly integrated, look brilliant and most importantly do what they are supposed to do best.</description></item></channel></rss>