<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hedge Fund Systems on Noverse</title><link>https://noverse.com/tags/hedge-fund-systems/</link><description>Recent content in Hedge Fund Systems on Noverse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 14:33:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noverse.com/tags/hedge-fund-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hiltmonisms for Hedge Funds</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/12/hiltmonisms-for-hedge-funds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 14:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/12/hiltmonisms-for-hedge-funds/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span class="light">This post is another part in a series on &lt;strong>Hedge Fund Systems&lt;/strong>, a series of posts based on my experience in the design, implementation, issues and thoughts involved in crafting an end-to-end platform for a complex Hedge Fund.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the things I have been writing about on my personal blog over the past few years is a set of &lt;strong>Hiltmonisms&lt;/strong> - a bunch of maxims based on the collected experiences of my mentors and my own - on how to best create software and systems for businesses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this series on &lt;strong>Hedge Fund Systems&lt;/strong> I have referred to these maxims in passing. In this post I spend a bit of time looking at the &lt;strong>Hiltmonisms&lt;/strong> most applicable to Hedge Fund systems software design and development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Hedge Fund Technology Architecture</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/06/a-hedge-fund-technology-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 09:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/06/a-hedge-fund-technology-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span class="light">This post is another part in a series on &lt;a href="https://noverse.com/blog/categories/hedge-fund-systems/">Hedge Fund Systems&lt;/a>, a series of posts based on my experience in the design, implementation, issues and thoughts involved in crafting an end-to-end platform for a complex Hedge Fund.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a modified version of my original 2004 architecture plan for a Hedge Fund. See &lt;a href="https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/04/the-opportunity/">The Opportunity&lt;/a> for how it came about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post I cover the objectives of the architecture, walk through the architecture itself and provide an overview of &lt;code>The Greeks&lt;/code>, our implementation thereof.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Opportunity</title><link>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/04/the-opportunity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 16:48:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://noverse.com/blog/2013/05/04/the-opportunity/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span class="light">This post is the first part of a series on &lt;strong>Hedge Fund Systems&lt;/strong>, a series of posts based on my experience in the design, implementation, issues and thoughts involved in crafting an end-to-end platform for a complex Hedge Fund.&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The year was 2004 and I was being offered a new job to be the Chief Technology Officer of a brand spanking new Hedge Fund that would trade &lt;em>everything&lt;/em> and launch within 6 months. Would I be interested in creating and managing a completely new technology platform to handle the end-to-end business needs of this new Wall Street firm?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would I? You bet I would!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the story of how I got the chance to design, create and grow a new financial business&amp;rsquo;s technology platform from scratch. And as amazing as it sounds, it all happened, it&amp;rsquo;s all true.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>